- Previously on "The Ark."
- That doctor said something
about me being the one.
What the hell
is Drake doing to them?
- It's like
some kind of puzzle.
That feels like progress.
- I had to go to freaking space
to get away from him.
- Gen-3 brain cells
are unstable,
and they do develop psychosis.
[explosion booming]
- Generators don't just
explode without reason.
- What are you implying?
- This is what
Angus was wearing
the last time I saw him.
- The "Ark 1" shuttle is gone.
- Find her.
- But I'm not Gen-3.
- Yes, darling, you are.
[dramatic music]
[laughter]
- She don't look too good.
- You all right, sis?
- Let's just say
I'm having a difficult time
believing I'm a Gen-3 clone.
- Mm.
- What can I say, darling?
You are.
- Can you explain
how that can be?
- It just--it doesn't track.
She never went psychotic.
- Which is exactly why
Kurtis has been
looking for you.
He wants to use you
to find a way
to stop the Gen-3s
from ever turning.
- If that's the case,
why didn't Drake just tell her?
- I'm guessing
he didn't think I'd be open
to impromptu brain surgery.
- Alls I know is he thinks
something inside of you
is the answer
to all his problems.
- You mean the problems
with the Gen-3s?
- Mm-mm.
That is not how he said it.
He specifically said,
"If I could just find
the right one, it would
solve all my problems."
- Mm.
[tense music]
♪ ♪
- Former EF and GSA personnel
are blaming each other
for the generator explosions.
We need to give them
the information--
- I'm afraid
he still hasn't woken,
so we know nothing about him.
- I've checked our manifests.
He isn't "EF-2."
- Are you certain?
- Absolutely.
- Well, he doesn't appear
on any Ark manifests.
- You must have
missed something.
GSA manifests are solid.
- As are EFs'.
- All right, so he's not
on either manifest.
The truth is he could be
a stowaway from either ship.
- But if he's been
hiding out all this time,
why expose himself now
to sabotage the generator?
- I don't know.
But as soon as
he regains consciousness,
we'll interrogate him
to find out.
- Any idea when that might be?
- [sighs] Well, I don't
even know if he'll wake up,
much less when.
- More important question is
are there more like him?
[dramatic music]
Saboteurs hiding among us.
[uplifting music]
♪ ♪
[metallic clanking]
- Glad you made it back safely.
- So sorry to hear about Brice.
He had my respect.
- Thank you.
And I'm sorry
about Doc Morozov.
She was a great addition
to "Ark 1."
Jill and Clark, the two clones
from Drake's ship,
they're on the next shuttle.
Can we find space for them?
- Are they a security risk?
- Uh, no, I don't think so.
- Then of course.
Consider it done.
- Any word on "EF-1"?
- None.
Tried everything.
No contact.
- I'm sorry.
- Captain.
[somber music]
- Excuse me.
♪ ♪
Eva.
- Strickland.
Have you found Angus?
- No. I'm so sorry.
We're still looking.
- OK.
Um, what can I do?
I want to help.
- Come with me.
I'll fill you in.
♪ ♪
[indistinct chatter]
- Not too shabby, eh?
- Yeah.
I know you said it was
beautiful, but wow.
Who is that?
- Oh, that's Ves.
Yeah, she's one of
the council members.
I think she came here
on "Ark 11."
[soft dramatic music]
- We can't find
any physical tracks,
no sign of a struggle.
The only thing
we came across was
an abnormality
in the vegetation.
- Well, what kind
of abnormality?
- It was strange.
A perfect circle of dead,
burnt vegetation.
We tested it to see
if there were any hints
of Kelly's or Angus's
whereabouts,
but there doesn't seem
to be a connection.
- Well, have you tried
tracing their WDs?
- Yes. Nothing.
No emergency beacon,
no signal at all.
- OK, well,
now that "Ark 1" is here,
we may be able
to tap into the array receiver
from the aft section.
- To do what?
- It's more sensitive
than the receivers
we use here to communicate
on Homebase,
so we may be able to pick up
Angus and Kelly's WDs
even if the signal's weak.
- Get started and let me know
if you need anything.
Oh, and Alicia.
I really miss
having you around.
Go.
[EKG beeping steadily]
- Sharon.
Oh, you're back. I'm--
I'm--I'm so sorry I couldn't
meet you at the shuttle.
It's been a crazy morning.
- Have you known all this time?
- Known what?
- That I'm Gen-3.
[soft dramatic music]
- Uh...
yes.
♪ ♪
- Sanji.
- But Dr. Hall
swore me to secrecy.
- Why?
- In addition
to the officially sanctioned
experiments that
Hall conducted on you,
he was also doing
unsanctioned ones to solve
the Gen-3 brain anomaly.
- Yeah, to stop them--
us from ever turning psychotic.
I know.
- Yeah, eventually,
one of the things
he tried on you
actually worked,
which is why
you haven't turned.
- If what you're saying
is true,
then why didn't he give it
to all the Gen-3s?
- Because he couldn't
reproduce the experiment.
He couldn't get it
to work on your sister.
Or--or any of the other Gen-3s.
[somber music]
♪ ♪
- Denise was Gen-3?
- Uh...
- He lied to us.
He said my sister and I
were Gen-2s.
- He swore me to secrecy when
he brought you on "Ark 1."
I couldn't tell you.
- But why?
- T-to protect you.
He didn't want other people
to find out you were Gen-3
and start experimenting on you.
- Like Drake tried to.
And he must have known somehow.
And it might help
if I knew about this, Sanji,
before I went to his ship.
♪ ♪
[birds singing]
[indistinct chatter]
- Thought I might
find you here.
I'll have what she's having.
So come on.
Out with it.
- How would you feel
if you just found out
you were the only Gen-3
in the universe
who's not psychotic?
- Mm.
Well, probably better than
the ones who are psychotic.
Thanks.
- Feel like I don't
know who I am anymore.
- Oh, come on.
You're kidding, right?
Gen-2, Gen-3,
Gen-1,000, doesn't matter.
You're still Sharon Garnet.
- Whatever Dr. Hall
did to me on Earth,
I survived and Denise didn't.
And it feels wrong.
- Mm.
The old survivor's guilt, eh?
Well, lucky for you,
I've got some experience
in that department too.
I grew up in a lab full of
clones all designed to die,
and yet, here I am.
Look, the only way
to move forwards
is to keep on doing
the good that you do.
Least that way, it doesn't feel
like it was all for nothing.
Curly.
- [chuckles]
- Look at me.
To keeping on keeping on?
- To keeping on keeping on.
- You asked for us?
- Is Sheriff Petrovic awake?
- I'm afraid not.
- What about our mystery man?
- No, but we have
new information
I thought the council
should know.
There's no change in
our John Doe's condition,
but we found something
you should see.
- This is an MRI scan
of his head.
- Yeah--if you look closely,
you'll see he has three sets
of cochleas in each ear.
- We all have one per ear.
- His vocal cords also
have noticeable differences
from ours.
- Was there something
that was done to him?
- There are no signs of surgery
or any other
medical interventions.
Far as I can tell,
he was born this way.
- Could he be a humanoid
who evolved here
the same way we did on Earth,
just with these
few differences?
- I don't know.
That's unlikely.
- I was on the first Ark
that arrived here.
We swept the area multiple
times for sign of life.
Nothing but plants and birds.
[soft suspenseful music]
- So who is he?
- A better question might be
what is he?
[suspenseful music]
[birds singing]
- Eva, I've been
looking for you.
Why aren't you out
fixing the generators?
- I am.
Oh.
I mean I will.
- What are you doing?
- OK, have to listen to this.
I triangulated a signal.
It's coming from Ross.
- Ross?
- Yes.
I think it's James.
Here. Listen.
[beeping]
[crackling electronic droning]
- [sighs] I don't--
[electronic chime]
- Just--OK, just listen again.
OK? There.
[electronic chime]
[crackling electronic droning]
There. At the end.
Hear it?
[electronic chime]
It's an unnatural modulation.
- That could be any kind
of interference.
A solar flare,
another radio signal.
Eva, this isn't healthy.
You have to let this go.
- Yeah, but what if
he's trying to--
- Eva.
James is gone.
I saw him die.
- But it feels wrong
to think about anything else.
- I know.
OK?
But the temperatures
are rising,
and we have a whole section
of the colony without power
and we need you.
[soft dramatic music]
So do you think you could go
and fix some generators?
♪ ♪
- OK.
- I'll let you have
some privacy.
♪ ♪
[door closes]
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
[EKG beeping steadily]
[tense music]
♪ ♪
[EKG beeping quickly]
- Who are you?
What do you want?
- What's going on?
- I don't know.
He just woke up.
I came to see if he's OK.
- OK, thank you.
I can take it from here.
My name is Dr. Kabir.
You're safe.
Can you tell me who you are?
Why is he so afraid of you?
- I-I don't know.
I should get back to work.
Let us know
if he says anything.
- OK. Thank you.
Hey, stay with me.
Stay with me.
You're OK. You're OK.
You're OK.
[birds singing]
- No one's going to rescue us.
You know that, right?
- Why do you say that?
- They probably think
I killed you
and gave up the search.
Isn't that what
you would think?
- Alicia won't let them
give up.
- You really love her,
don't you?
- That doesn't make you mad,
does it?
- No.
I'm so over you.
- Oh.
- I don't even know why
I was ever attracted to you.
- Thanks.
Thank you, I guess.
[sniffles]
- So is Alicia as into you
as you're into her?
- Where is this going, Kelly?
- Just trying
to gauge the odds
of the Homebase people
coming for us or not.
- She won't let them quit.
- Assuming she even knows.
She's a million light years
away on the Ark, remember?
[soft somber music]
- Damn.
I didn't even think of that.
[mechanical whirring]
[electricity crackling]
- Fuel levels are adequate
and the generator is grounded.
Did you turn on the fuel valve?
- Do you know,
I can't believe you think
so little of me, Markovic.
- OK, I'll take that as a yes.
Powering on?
- Let's do it.
[electricity thrumming]
[chuckles] Yeah.
Come on.
- I'm Captain Sharon Garnet.
Can you understand me?
[electricity thrumming]
Huh. Looks like Eva got one
of the generators working.
- [groaning]
- What's wrong with him?
- I don't know.
- [screaming]
- Are you OK? Talk to me.
- [groaning]
- Maybe it's the lights?
- [screaming]
We're hurting him somehow! I--
[tense music]
♪ ♪
[soft suspenseful music]
- Something to do
with the generator sound
was hurting his ears?
- Well, the extra cochlea
probably allow him
to hear frequencies
our ears can't.
Uh, the generators must emit
some kind of piercing,
high frequency sound?
- At least now we know
why he blew them up.
♪ ♪
- Good to see you
back in action, Eva.
- Thanks.
I just miss him.
- If you ever need
a shoulder to cry on,
I've got a spare one.
- Thank you.
- Aye, might not be quite
as big and as strapping
as Brice's was,
but it'll do in a pinch.
- I just have to make myself
accept that he's gone.
[somber music]
[electricity crackling]
- [panting]
[mechanical whirring]
[metallic rattling]
[dramatic music]
- Who's there?
- Lieutenant Brice?
It's me, Dr. Morozov.
- Where am I?
- We're still on Ross.
- How?
- I dragged you away
from those creatures outside.
I did my best to patch you up
with what I could find.
You've been out
for a long time.
- We, uh, we have to get
a signal to "Ark 1"
before it leaves orbit.
- I hate to tell you,
but "Ark 1" left days ago.
[tense music]
♪ ♪
[electricity crackling]
- The Admiral said
this structure was
on the verge of collapse.
- It could cave in
any minute now.
- Look, is there any way
to send a signal?
- Comms are in
another corridor.
They're too damaged.
And I don't know how to repair
our communications array
anyway.
- Yeah, it's a good job I do.
Listen, you get me to comms,
I should be able to fix it up
well enough to send a signal.
- No.
To get to it,
we have to pass them.
- The creatures?
- No, the raiders.
[metallic rumbling]
- Wait, I'm sorry.
The raiders?
- Yeah, nasty bunch.
I've decided
I really don't like them.
OK, if we want to go
to the comms, now's our chance.
[tense music]
♪ ♪
- Checking corridor D.
- They're here.
[gasps]
- [shushes]
♪ ♪
Who the hell are these guys?
[yelps]
♪ ♪
- Let me ask you something.
Do you think Alicia
would think I killed you
and give up the search?
- I mean, she did
have to stop you
from killing me that time
in the bio shelter.
- Yeah, to this day,
I still don't know
why I messed that up.
Ruined my perfect streak.
[laughs]
- You've got one
dark sense of humor.
- What other kind
would you expect me to have?
- Anyway...
to answer your question,
I think Alicia sees you
as a friend now.
Like I do.
- [chuckles]
You see me as a friend?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
I mean, let's face it.
You're...
not the same person you were
when your mother was
controlling you.
[stone scraping]
What are you doing?
[suspenseful music]
- I think I know
how we can get out.
♪ ♪
Come on, we can crawl through.
- [grunts and pants]
No!
[metallic creaking]
[birds singing]
- If there's a signal
from Angus or Kelly's WDs,
this should amplify it
and allow us to trace it
to its origin point.
It's picking up something,
but it's too faint.
- Is there any way
you can turn it up?
- It's already close
to max power, but I'll try.
I don't want to blow the coil.
[device chiming]
Oh, I've got him.
- Can you get a direction?
- No. The reading's still
not strong enough.
- Turn it up some more.
- I'm afraid
it'll blow the coil.
- Is there something else
you can do?
If we can't get a direction,
the signal does us no good.
- If it blows out,
we may never find them.
- [sighs] If we can't get
a direction for the signal,
we may also never find them.
- OK.
[groans]
[sighs]
[WD chimes]
- Strickland to Garnet.
- Go for Garnet.
- The phased array didn't work.
We searched everywhere
in the zone.
I don't know what else to do.
- I might have an idea.
John Doe seems to be
pretty mobile now.
Kabir got him up to go
to the bathroom.
He can walk.
- I don't follow.
- Well, he's wearing
Angus's clothing,
but you already checked
Angus's cabin, right?
- Yeah, no signs of foul play.
- So maybe he got the clothing
right off Angus's back.
[tense music]
♪ ♪
- Lieutenant Ilic.
- That is my last name,
but I wasn't military.
- Oh.
- How have been
settling in, Admiral?
- Uh...
yeah, what's--
what's not to like?
[chuckling]
Right?
- Well, I heard you caused
quite a stir
taking over command of "Ark 1."
- What can I say?
I like to shake things up.
- I expect you'll be wanting
to shake things up here
as well?
- Well, I have
a couple of ideas.
- Maybe I can show you
around Homebase.
- I'd like that.
I could have sworn we've had
some overlap at GSA command.
- No.
Like I said, I wasn't military.
- I mean, you have a face
that would be hard to forget.
- Oh, I'll take that
as a compliment.
- It is a compliment.
But it must mean you have
a clone at GSA command.
- There are no clones of me,
as far as I know.
[WD chimes]
Mm. I'm sorry.
You'll have to excuse me.
I have a meeting to get to.
- Got to do what we have to do.
- [chuckles softly]
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
[ominous music]
- He's coming your way.
♪ ♪
- Got him on the tracker.
- [groans softly]
[indistinct chatter]
- He's leaving the safe zone.
- Do we follow?
- Eva said we have 5K buffer
before the air gets bad.
- Breadcrumb it and keep track
of how far we go.
- Copy.
[tense music]
♪ ♪
[soft suspenseful music]
Well, that's new.
- What is that?
♪ ♪
[rumbling]
[tense music]
♪ ♪
- What the hell was that?
- I don't know.
But I'm going after him.
Cover me.
♪ ♪
There's nothing here.
- What if we touch the stone
like he did?
[soft suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
Anything?
- Strickland to Garnet.
- Go for Garnet.
- We found where he must
have been hiding out,
but we can't get in.
- What do you mean?
- The entrance is
camouflaged somehow.
- You're gonna want to see this
for yourself, Captain.
- Send me the coordinates.
I'll meet you there.
♪ ♪
- OK.
- [sighs]
Wipe it down with
those antiseptic wipes.
- Yep.
- OK.
- OK, here.
Take this.
You have to fix me.
- Like, um...
I don't want to hurt you.
- Just sew it up like
you're sewing up a seam.
- Right.
[clears throat]
[soft suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
- [groaning softly]
- Ah--sorry, sorry.
[sighs]
[soft dramatic music]
So, uh, what made you want
to become a medic, anyway?
- [chuckles softly]
The truth is I've always
been kind of a caretaker.
It's like...
it's what I was made to do.
[gasps]
- Sorry, sorry.
I think clearly, it is not
what I was made to do.
[both chuckle]
♪ ♪
- Ooh.
[clicks tongue]
Bad day.
I had a feeling
I might find you here.
- I'm flattered you find me
so interesting, Admiral.
- You are very intriguing.
Lieutenant Commander.
[tense music]
- I told you I'm not military.
- Really?
That's not what our
military records say.
And the strange thing is
there are a lot of redactions.
Huge swaths
of blacked-out information.
[sighs]
So tell me.
Who are you?
- You ask a lot of questions.
- Just trying
to get to know you.
♪ ♪
- If I were you,
I'd lose interest.
[tense music]
♪ ♪
- Wow.
Who could have built this?
- Amazing, isn't it?
- Our man opened the hatch
with this thing and went in,
which means Angus and Kelly
could be inside.
- A hatch?
- He touched the stone
in some sort of pattern.
- Like, uh, this.
- And a hatch opened
over there,
but we can't seem
to reproduce what he did.
There aren't any buttons
or anything.
- Is it possible he's
the only one that can open it?
Maybe there's something
special about him.
- He does have
different ears from us.
Could the mechanism have
something to do with sound?
- Maybe this door is activated
by something outside
of the range of our hearing.
I might be able to use
my WD to look for a sound
and transpose the frequency
into a range we can hear.
[WD buzzing]
[musical notes warbling]
There.
Those notes are
coming from the stone.
My WD is adjusting it
into our hearing range.
[musical notes warbling]
- Sounds like a musical scale.
- It's a C major scale,
but it's missing three notes.
[musical notes warbling]
I used to play piano.
- Really?
- What if you touched the stone
in the same way he did,
but only when you hear
a gap in the scale?
- OK.
[musical notes warbling]
♪ ♪
[rumbling]
- That is so cool.
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
You really think
they're down there?
- Only one way to find out.
- Flashlights out.
♪ ♪
- Stay alert.
Who knows what's waiting
for us down there?
And alert Homebase
that we're going in.
♪ ♪
[suspenseful music]
- Captain, look.
♪ ♪
- That's just like
the slab Angus found.
♪ ♪
- This can't be a natural cave.
It must've been built
by someone.
- Yeah, but who?
Or what?
♪ ♪
- What was that?
- I don't know.
- Stay close.
♪ ♪
- So this is where
you've been sleeping.
- [groans]
Yeah.
Didn't feel comfortable
in our cabin.
- I--
I never said
you couldn't sleep there.
- [sighs]
I know.
But I know
you were angry with me
because of the way
I reacted to...
- Yeah.
Hey, Sanji.
- Mm?
- I'm really sorry.
It's just that guy,
he gets under my skin.
- Yeah.
How do you think I feel?
- [sighs]
- She's a piece of work,
isn't she?
- [sighs]
- I know you don't like me.
- Oh, yeah?
- You got it all wrong.
It's not all my fault.
Sanji can be
a real bitch sometimes.
[coughing]
[tense music]
♪ ♪
- Which way do we go?
- Heavier foot traffic
in the tunnel to the right.
- So let's go that way.
♪ ♪
- Maybe they won't feed us
anymore after what I did.
- They want us alive.
- OK. I just--
I think that they might--
[stone scraping]
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
She's--
- Human.
- [harmonic screaming]
- Let her go!
- Just slide under
the door first.
- You saw what happened
to that tray!
- They won't do that
to one of their own.
- [harmonic screaming]
- OK, but if I end up
flattened, that's on you!
- [harmonic screaming]
♪ ♪
- [gasps]
- [harmonic screaming]
[tense music]
♪ ♪
- Uh, Angus?
Who are they?
- I got no idea.
- That one's
wearing your clothes.
- Please, please,
just tell us what you want.
- Get back!
♪ ♪
[soft suspenseful music]
[WD chiming]
♪ ♪
- It's Kelly and Angus's WDs.
We're getting a signal.
This way.
- Don't worry.
I have my implants turned on.
- No, Kelly.
Kelly, don't hurt them unless
it's obvious
they're gonna hurt us.
- I'm not letting them
put us back in that room.
- Hey, hey, please.
We don't want to hurt you.
Listen, tell us what you want.
What do you want from us?
[tense music]
[all screaming]
What's happening?
[high-pitched ringing playing]
- [gasps] Angus!
[soft dramatic music]
Angus.
- I don't understand.
What--what chased them off?
- I-I used my WD
to duplicate a frequency
that hurts their ears.
- How'd you know
how to do that?
- Come on.
Let's save it
for when we get out of here.
[dramatic music]
[electrical thumping]
- [sighs] Looks good.
Power is restored.
- Mm, yep.
Nobody will notice
the difference.
- Yeah, except the people
in those caves.
- I hope it wasn't a mistake
lowering the VCN frequency.
- Well, Sharon thought it might
be a good peace offering
to, you know,
stop hurting the locals' ears.
- Except it could have been
all that was keeping them
from attacking us.
[tense music]
- mm.
♪ ♪
- You did some serious damage.
- I told her to stop
hitting the wall.
- Your nanites should take care
of it fairly quickly,
but you should keep it clean.
- Uh, can you stay still?
I'm trying to take
your blood pressure.
- Sorry.
- Is he OK?
- Far as I can tell, he's fine.
- We're glad you're both safe,
but we need to ask you
a few questions
about what you saw down there.
- How many people did you see
before Garnet arrived?
- Were they violent toward you?
- They were, uh--
- It's also important
we understand
what kinds of power sources
they have.
- Were they armed?
- They need to rest.
- This can't wait.
We need to know
what we're dealing with.
- It can wait until tomorrow.
- All right.
Until tomorrow.
- Thank you.
Rest up.
- Um--sorry, one second.
Can I talk to you for a minute?
- I don't have time.
- Sharon, just hear me out.
Once Dr. Hall died,
I should have told you.
- Yes, you should have.
- But you were so worried about
ending up like your sister,
I didn't want
to exacerbate that worry
by telling you
you were Gen-3.
- That was not
your decision to make.
- You're right. I'm sorry.
You said Drake had a room
full of Gen-3s on his ship?
- At least one.
- Then who knows
how many more Gen-3s
could be out there, right?
I mean, Drake's company made
a lot of clones.
- Is there a point?
- Yes.
Drake thought he could find
the answer in you,
but he didn't have
one thing I do.
Dr. Hall's research.
- OK, but you said
he couldn't reproduce the cure.
- Well, he might have
had he lived long enough.
Let's finish his work.
[soft dramatic music]
- Uh, so you want
to experiment on me?
- No.
I-I want to find a cure.
Together.
♪ ♪
- I would like that.
- [sighs]
Really?
- Come here.
Bring it in.
Jerk. I really wanted
to stay mad at you.
- I'm sorry.
- Me too.
♪ ♪
- Can I help you
with something, Admiral?
- Cut the BS.
- I'm sorry?
- Now, I was
pleasantly surprised
to see that
my Admiral clearance code
still gave me access
to redacted files.
I got to read all about you.
I always thought
Black Thorn was a rumor.
Tell me, do your cohorts on
the council know about this?
[soft suspenseful music]
- You know...
I really wished
you let this go.
- [groans]
[tense music]
♪ ♪
[somber music]
[groans]
♪ ♪
- Shit.
[tense music]
♪ ♪
- I'm close.
Just need to adjust
the frequency
to get the signal out.
♪ ♪
- Someone's coming.
Keep going.
- Rebooting now.
- [gasps]
♪ ♪
- Come on, come on.
- Keep going!
[computer chimes]
- Yes! It sent!
[gunshots]
♪ ♪
[screams]
[tense somber music]
No, no, no.
Hey, hey, hey. Hey.
Stay with me, Doc.
OK?
- You have to fix me.
Buddy.
♪ ♪
- No.
No, no, no, no.
[computerized warbling]
♪ ♪
What the hell?
[computer chimes]
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
[somber music]